{"Topic": "Rivers - Miscellaneous Info", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Questions : Rivers - Ancient Names, Disputes etc.", "op1": "Jhelum", "op2": "Indus", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Ravi", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Battle of Hydaspes between Alexander and King porous was fought on the banks of River Hydaspes which is now known as -", "op1": "Karnataka", "op2": "Tamilnadu", "op3": "Odisha", "op4": "Maharashtra", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which state along with Andhra Pradesh is involved in the Vansadhara Water dispute?", "op1": "Andhra Pradesh", "op2": "Kerala", "op3": "Karnataka", "op4": "Puducherry", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Mullaperiyar Dam is a matter of dispute between Tamilnadu and -?", "op1": "Krishna", "op2": "Chambal", "op3": "Narmada", "op4": "Tapti", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers flows towards the north?", "op1": "Karnataka", "op2": "Andhra Pradesh", "op3": "Goa", "op4": "Madhya Pradesh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Babhali barrage issue is a matter of dispute between Maharashtra and", "op1": "Sutlej", "op2": "Beas", "op3": "Ravi", "op4": "Jhelum", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers was known as Parusni in ancient times?", "op1": "Chenab", "op2": "Narmada", "op3": "Jhelum", "op4": "Beas", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers was known as Vipasa in the ancient times?", "op1": "Kerala, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu", "op2": "Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu", "op3": "Karnataka and Tamil Nadu", "op4": "Kerala and Tamil Nadu", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The states through which the Cauvery river flows is", "op1": "Damodar", "op2": "Gandak", "op3": "Kosi", "op4": "Sone", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following river is known as \u2018Sorrow of Bengal\u2019?", "op1": "the Krishna", "op2": "the Sindh", "op3": "the Narmada", "op4": "the Cauvery", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "An Indian river that does not form any delta is :", "op1": "The Indus", "op2": "The Ganga", "op3": "The Brahmaputra", "op4": "the Mahanadi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers has the largest river basin in India?", "op1": "The Ravi", "op2": "The Indus", "op3": "The Chenab", "op4": "The Jhelum", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers is not included in Panchnad?", "op1": "Ghaghara", "op2": "The Kosi", "op3": "The Gandak", "op4": "The Ken", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers is notorious for changing its course frequently?", "op1": "Mahanadi", "op2": "Krishna", "op3": "Godavari", "op4": "Kaveri", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is the largest river of the peninsular India?", "op1": "The Narmada", "op2": "The Kaveri", "op3": "The Tapi", "op4": "The Krishna"}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers flows in a rift valley?", "op1": "The Chambal", "op2": "The Sone", "op3": "The Narmada", "op4": "The Luni", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers forms estuary in place of delta?", "op1": "The Narmada", "op2": "The Kaveri", "op3": "The Mahanadi", "op4": "The Godavari", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a Trans-Himalayan river?", "op1": "Indus", "op2": "Ganges", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Brahmaputra", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a river of inland water drainage?", "op1": "Chambal", "op2": "Luni", "op3": "Rupen", "op4": "Ghaggar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers is known as Singi Khamban in Tibet?", "op1": "Sutlej", "op2": "Brahmaputra", "op3": "Jhelum", "op4": "Indus", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The river with the highest tidal bore in India is -", "op1": "Cauvery", "op2": "Mahanadi", "op3": "Hoogli", "op4": "Krishna", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The river Rangit flows through which of the following states?", "op1": "Sikkim", "op2": "Nagaland", "op3": "Manipur", "op4": "Tripura", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers does not flow into Pakistan?", "op1": "Jhelum", "op2": "Beas", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Chenab", "Answer": 3}]}